ANDRA STEELE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



949-910-7723



andrasteele@gmail.com



Portland, Oregon



/in/andra-steele

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

PNW-based software engineer passionate about collaborative and creative approaches to elegant software solutions. My experience is informed by almost a decade of work within the hospitality sector as a chef as well as an academic background in sociology and law. I specialize in back-end development with interests in machine learning and user experience.

SKILLS

Node.js

React & React Native

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Git

TypeScript

RESTful API Development

Test Driven Development (TDD)

HTML & CSS

Python

MongoDB

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I

SciTab Consulting, Portland, Oregon | 07/2023 - Present

- Write scripts for implementing custom modules of high-definition image export and custom stencils for tattoo artists.
- Created Jest testing suites to ensure application functionality.
- Sketched whiteboards for showcasing workflows of prospective feature build-outs for client review.
- Spearheaded documentation for application usage and deployment.
- Technologies used: React Native, Expo Go, GitLab, Typescript

Sales Representative

Revel Meat Co., Canby, Oregon | 07/2021 - Present

- Administered a product traceability program utilizing SQL databases within USDA-required constraints.
- Manage several accounts throughout the Portland metro area, increasing total sales by 70%.

ION Chef de Cuisine

Jon & Vinny's, Los Angeles, California | 10/2018 - 03/2020

- Maintained Michelin Bib Gourmand status throughout restaurant tenure.
- Led a team of over ten chefs in food preparation, cooking, and service.
- Automated ordering processes for back of house operations.

EDUCATION

|| Certificate in Advanced Software Development

Code Fellows Seattle, Washington 2022-2023

|| Bachelor's in Sociology

University of Texas at Austin Austin, Texas 2011 – 2015